gototraining.com 2016-12-21

# Citrix Online Privacy Policy - Citrix

GetGo, Inc., is committed to respecting your privacy. This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices for GoToMeeting ([www.gotomeeting.com](http://www.gotomeeting.com/)), GoToWebinar ([www.gotowebinar.com](http://www.gotowebinar.com/)), GoToTraining ([www.gototraining.com](http://www.gototraining.com/)), GoToMyPC ([www.gotomypc.com](http://www.gotomypc.com/)), GoToAssist ([www.gotoassist.com](http://www.gotoassist.com/)) and the websites and related mobile services provided by GetGo.

From time to time, GetGo may introduce new products and services. To the extent that these new products and services affect this policy, this policy will be updated. Please see item number 6 for details on how we notify users of updates to our privacy policy.

Privacy Shield

GetGo participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.  GetGo has committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable principles.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>.

GetGo is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequent transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf.  GetGo complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred to the Privacy Shield Framework, GetGo is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.  In certain situations, GetGo may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>, you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

GetGo complies with the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from Switzerland.  GetGo has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view GetGo’s certification, please visit <https://safeharbor.export.gov/swisslist.aspx>.

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us here. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

## Contents

  1. Why is my information needed?
  2. Where is my information stored?
  3. What information does GetGo gather/track and how is it used?
  4. With whom does GetGo share the information?
  5. How can I review, correct and update my personal information?
  6. How can I opt out of GetGo’s collection, use and distribution of my information?
  7. How does GetGo protect my information from loss, misuse or alteration?
  8. What does GetGo do with Send a Friend a Free Trial/Referral information?
  9. What does GetGo do with information submitted through the Become a Partner link?
  10.   Who can I ask if I have additional questions?

#### 1\. Why is my information needed?

We collect information from you that is necessary to provide the service to you. Our services are subscription-based; because of this they may require you to set up an account that uses first and last names, billing contact information, a password and a valid email address as a login. We may combine the information we collect from you with information obtained from other outside sources to validate email or provide additional information such as company industry, company size, and employee size. This helps us improve its overall accuracy and completeness, and also helps us better tailor our interactions with you. Personal data may be collected in order to provide authentication, access to our services, and diagnostic information. We may also collect information about the use of the services in order to monitor and run our services, to provide support, and to provide reports to our users.

Back to top ▲

#### 2\. Where is my information stored?

GetGo is headquartered in the United States of America and maintains a global infrastructure.    Information that we collect and maintain may be transferred to, or controlled and processed in, the United States and/or other countries around the world. When you provide us with information, or use our website(s) and services, you consent to this transfer.  GetGo previously certified under the EU and Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of data from the European Union and Switzerland.  Although EU Safe Harbor was invalidated by the Court of Justice of the European Union in October, 2015, GetGo continues to adhere to Swiss Safe Harbor, and the Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  However, GetGo makes available other means by which we and our customers can comply with EU law for transferring and processing data. We will protect the privacy and security of personal information we collect in accordance with this privacy policy, regardless of where it is processed or stored.

#### 3\. What information does GetGo gather/track and how is it used?

Information collected will vary by activity and may include personal information or other information which may be necessary to provide products, services, and information to you. These activities include when you register for a free trial or account, when you use the services or participate in events, surveys, or otherwise correspond or request information from us.

PERSONAL INFORMATION: We collect personal information from users who purchase services, including (at minimum) first and last names, an email address to be used as a login, billing contact information, credit card number and a password. GetGo will take steps to validate the credit card and billing information supplied to us to ensure it is accurate. When a user uses a service, registers online for a free trial of a service, or otherwise establishes an account or identity with us, GetGo will collect (at a minimum) first and last names, and an email address to be used as a login. Your email address may be used to send you periodic product newsletters, offers and usage tips from GetGo. You can opt out of promotional emails at any time by following the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of each communication, but will still receive “transactional” communications such as receipts, confirmation emails and customer service updates that are considered necessary to provide the service to you. We use the information collected to deliver services, process payments, allow you to invite users to sign up for the site, set up accounts for other users within your organization, update our records, communicate with you about products and services, and generally maintain your accounts with us. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active, as needed to provide you services, to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, or if you believe that one of your contacts has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request it be removed from our database, contact us [here](http://support.citrixonline.com/en_US/GoToMeeting/case). We do not share, sell, trade, or rent your personal information to third parties except as described in this privacy policy.

SESSION INFORMATION **:**   Session information is information about activities and events associated with the use of our services.  When a service is “in-session” this includes information about screen sharing, keyboard/mouse control, webcam and audio usage, attentiveness of participants (as determined by whether the service is the active window), text chat or other content exchanged during a session, such as polls and handouts.  Screen sharing data, keyboard/mouse control data and text chat information collected during meeting, webinar and training sessions is protected by the use of end-to-end encryption and only accessible by the authorized users, organizers and participants unless cloud-based recording is used or the organizer has given permission for it to be accessed by others.

Information about scheduled and prior sessions, for example attendee lists, subject names, and session records, is stored by our service and is available to our customers, and may be made available to their authenticated users.  We may use session information to provide reports to organizers about their session and attendee participation and activity.  We may also use session information to monitor and improve our Service.

SESSION DATA: To maintain our quality of service and to assist in the analysis of product performance, we may also gather data on connection information, including the timing and size of all packets sent over the Internet during a session. The gathered information is used only to ensure the highest quality experience possible when using GetGo products.

SECURITY INFORMATION: GetGo also collects certain standard information about your computer or device for security and identification purposes. This information may include: IP addresses, domain names, access times, cookies and other unique identifying information of machines that have our software downloaded and installed on them. This information is used for the operation of the service, to identify and protect our customers and to control unauthorized use or abuse of our services. All information is encrypted during transmission and is stored securely within our servers.

GoToAssist has an unattended support permission-based feature and access must be set up in advance and with the approval of the owner of the unattended machine. The person providing unattended support must provide a strong password, and all network activity is encrypted using both SSL and AES encryption, so only the approved support provider can gain access via the Unattended Support link. The responsibility for security then rests on the relationship of trust between the support provider and the customer. Because it is a 100 percent permission-based feature, the customer has the ability to block or disable Unattended Support access at any time, temporarily or permanently.

BUSINESS INFORMATION: Information that is collected by our products or by meeting, webinar and training organizers or administrators is considered confidential. We will not view Business Information except as necessary to provide, improve, or support the service, to provide reports to users, or as required by law. Business Information includes schedules, attendee lists, subject names, email addresses, names, session records, meeting recordings, and any other business information used while in session.

MEETING ATTENDEES:  When an attendee registers with one of our customers for an online meeting, webinar or training, that information is provided to the organizer of the session. GetGo may store that information to fulfill our obligation to our customers, but we will not use the information to send marketing communications for GetGo services or third party offers to attendees.

CHAT LOGS:   You should be aware that any personal information you submit while in session and utilizing the chat feature can be read, collected or used by the meeting organizer and other meeting participants. Chat logs are not stored or viewable by GetGo and are only available locally to meeting organizers and attendees.

RECORDINGS:  Meeting recordings are stored locally unless the organizer elects to store meetings in the GetGo Cloud. Meeting recordings stored in GetGo Cloud may be accessible by any meeting attendee or guest and may be shared with non-attendees by any other meeting attendee or guest. We will not view recordings, except as necessary to appropriately support the service and for the purpose of anticipating, diagnosing, supporting or resolving any problems that might limit or disrupt the quality of our customers’ service experience or as required by law.

SURVEYS: In addition to required member information, we may conduct surveys and ask users to volunteer demographic and other information to be used on an aggregate basis for internal market research, presentation to advertisers and joint research projects with outside companies involved in product development. We use such information to better focus our product and personalize the scope of services offered to each individual user.

Because of our commitment to present the best possible product to all our users, we track the category of services selected by our individual users as well as all information pertaining to user satisfaction. To ensure the quality of our product, we reserve the right to maintain evaluation and feedback records.

PARTNERS: In some cases we provide services or sell product lines jointly with other businesses. For these co-branded offerings in which a third party is involved in your transactions, we will sometimes share or jointly collect customer information related to those transactions with that third party. On the co-branded registration pages we will state who is collecting or receiving the information and whose privacy policy governs its use so that you will know at the time you create your account exactly how your information will be used.

AFFILIATES: We may sometimes share or jointly collect information with our parent entity and the wholly owned subsidiaries and affiliated divisions of our parent company entity. Sharing this information helps us make your customer experience more seamless and efficient by allowing us to improve our marketing efforts to better target customer needs, streamline our processes and consolidate our backend business systems.

SOCIAL MEDIA: Our Site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook, Google and Twitter buttons. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. These services will also authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form or provide feedback. These Services may give you the option to post information about our products or your activities on our websites to your profile page to share with others within your network. You may also be allowed to start, send invitations to sessions, and join sessions through services such as Google Hangouts and HipChat.  Information will be exchanged between those services and ours when you perform these actions. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them.

BLOGS & TESTIMONIALS: Information gathered on our blogs is done so on a voluntary basis. You need not provide us with any personal information to use these sites. Information submitted on these sites can include contact information such as email addresses, comments on blog postings and job and press inquiries. You should be aware that any information you provide in the comment or blog areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from these areas, contact us [here](http://support.citrixonline.com/en_US/Meeting/case). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

With your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us via one of the methods listed in this Privacy Policy.

ANALYTICS: We continuously improve our websites and our products and we utilize different third party web analytics tools to help us do so. We are interested in how visitors use our websites, our desktop tools, our mobile applications, what they like and dislike, and where they have problems. Our products, desktop tools and mobile applications use analytical tools to understand feature usage patterns, to enhance and improve your product experience and offer you specific usage tips and guidance. In connection with normal business operations, as well as to increase functionality and enhance your user experience, this usage information may be linked to personal information that we have about individual users. We maintain ownership of this data and we do not share this type of data about individual users with third parties.

Our mobile applications also use analytical tools to help gather non-personal data about download and application usage. In our use of mobile applications we may utilize precise GeoLocation data but only if you specifically opt-in to collection of such data in connection with a particular service. We may use information such as IP addresses to determine the general geographic locations areas of our visitors, but this information is not correlated to personal information about individual users. The web beacons used in conjunction with these tools may gather data such as what browser a person uses, what operating systems are used, domain names, MIME types, what is downloaded, and what content, products and services are reviewed when visiting or registering for services at one of our websites or using one of our mobile applications.

This information is used solely to assist GetGo in maintaining more effective and useful websites and products for our customers. This data will not be shared with third parties in a way that can identify you without your prior consent or unless required by law.

GOOGLE ANALYTICS:  We use Google Analytics as described in [“How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps.”](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/) You can prevent your data from being used by Google Analytics on websites by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).  We also employ IP address masking, a technique used to truncate IP addresses collected by Google Analytics and store them in an abbreviated form to prevent them from being traced back to individual users. We may also use Google Analytics Demographics and Interests. We use the data provided by this service (such as age range, gender and interests) to better understand our website and app audience and tune our communications appropriately. Portions of our website may also use Google Analytics for Display Advertisers including DoubleClick or Dynamic Remarketing which provide interest-based ads based on your visit to this or other websites.  You can use [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads) to manage the Google ads you see and opt-out of interest-based ads.

TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES: We and our partners use cookies, beacons, tags and scripts to collect and track information and to improve our service. A cookie is a small data file that certain websites write to your hard drive when you visit them. We use cookies to track user traffic patterns and hold certain registration information. When you register at GetGo sites, we use cookies to store unique, randomly assigned user IDs that we generate for administrative purposes. These cookies enable you to enter the GetGo sites without having to log on each time. We do not collect or store passwords or any Personal Information about you in the cookies. We may also use cookies or other similar technologies in partnership with selected marketing companies to help us track the effectiveness of our websites, generate visitor traffic, display advertisements based upon your browsing activities and interests on our website, to manage our advertising on other sites or as part of a referral program.

If you wish to not have the information these technologies collect used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/), or if located in the European Union, click [here.](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. You can still review the website if you choose to set your browser to refuse all cookies; however, you must enable cookies in order to establish an account and to download and install any of the software.

Back to top ▲  

#### 4\. With whom does getgo share the information?

Ensuring your privacy is important to us. We do not sell, trade or rent your personal information to third parties.

GetGo products and services by necessity require us to provide some of your information to third parties. We may occasionally employ other companies to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include processing credit card payments, sending postal mail and email, analyzing data, providing or supporting service functionality, supporting the service, and providing marketing assistance. They have access to personal information needed only to perform their functions and may not use it for any other purpose. Further, they must process the personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Also, in the event that GetGo or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will be one of the transferred assets. For more information on how you will be notified in this instance, see Section 6 below.

Occasionally we send offers to select groups of GetGo customers on behalf of other businesses. When we do this, we do not share your personal information with the other businesses. Except in the limited instances as stated above, we will never voluntarily share personal information with any third party without the user’s express consent or unless compelled by applicable state and federal laws. GetGo does not control the practices of our third-party partners. If you have questions about how partners use the information gathered when you link to them, please read their privacy policies.

This website may contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by GetGo. Please be aware that we, GetGo, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects personal information.

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law or legal process, in response to a request by law enforcement authorities, when we believe that disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect our rights or to prevent physical harm or financial loss, or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity, or to respond to a government request. We may also disclose your personal information to any other third party with your prior consent.

Back to top ▲  

#### 5\. How can I review, correct and update my personal information?

Upon request GetGo will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information.  To request this information please, contact us at [privacy@getgo.com](mailto:privacy@getgo.com).  If you wish to change or review your personal information, go to your My Account page. There you can access or update the personal information and account history we have on file. Regardless of account status, if we hold personal information about you, you will be afforded the opportunity to correct, amend, or delete that information where it is inaccurate, or has been processed in violation of this policy, except where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to an individual’s privacy in the case in question, or where the rights of persons other than the individual requesting access would be violated.   Please contact us [here](http://support.citrixonline.com/en_US/GoToMeeting/case) if you need assistance in updating or reviewing your information. GetGo will respond to your access request to review the information we have on file for you within a reasonable time.

Back to top ▲  

#### 6\. How can I opt out of GetGo’s collection, use and distribution of my information?

To change your email subscription status to receive or to stop receiving marketing communications or third-party promotions administered by GetGo or, where applicable, to opt out of GetGo’s collection, use and distribution of your information as stated above, follow the instructions on the email or go to the [Unsubscribe page](http://learn.citrix.com/NE-Unsubscribe.html), enter your email address and then click Submit. Users who would like to deactivate their account can contact us [here](http://support.citrixonline.com/en_US/GoToMeeting/case) for assistance.

This privacy policy is subject to change. If we are going to use your personal information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, we will provide notice on the website of such material change. If GetGo or any of its assets are acquired by another company we will make reasonable efforts to notify you.  In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our website notifying users of the change.

Back to top ▲  

#### 7\. How does GetGo protect my information from loss, misuse or alteration?

GetGo uses industry-standard administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use of your personal information, including encryption, firewalls and SSL (Secure Sockets Layer). Nevertheless, we remind you that no security measure is perfect.

GetGo is not liable for loss of passwords due to user carelessness. If you lose control over your password, you may lose control over your personal information. If you believe your password has been compromised, we recommend that you immediately change your password. For information on how to do this, please see item number 5 above.

Back to top ▲  

#### 8\. What does GetGo do with Send to a Friend or Referral information?  

Most of our referral programs will provide email text or links that may be sent to a friend or colleague using the sender’s own email account. Some programs require users to submit name, e-mail address or other personal information about themselves or their friends or colleagues. In such cases, this information will only be used by GetGo or a third-party administrator acting on our behalf to administer the program.

Back to top ▲  

#### 9\. What does GetGo do with information submitted through the Become a Partner link?

Information submitted to us via the GetGo Referral Partner Program is completely voluntary and enables us to provide you with information on GetGo partnership opportunities. All information submissions are voluntary and will be used solely to provide information to you at your request. In keeping with our privacy policy standards, we will never voluntarily share personal information submitted to us about partnership opportunities with any third party without your express consent or unless compelled by applicable state and federal laws.

Back to top ▲  

#### 10.Who can I ask if I have additional questions?

For additional inquiries about the privacy of your information, you can contact GetGo [here](http://support.citrixonline.com/en_US/GoToMeeting/case), by calling +1 805 690 6400 or by writing to us via regular mail at: GetGo, 7414 Hollister Avenue, Goleta, CA 93117. To reach our Global Customer Support department, you may contact us [here](http://support.citrixonline.com/en_US/GoToMeeting/case).

Back to top ▲
